If you're [music] like many physical
injury claimants, you may have some
questions about your settlement options.
For [music] 40 years, Credential has
helped settlement recipients achieve
financial security through a structured
settlement. [music] And now we offer an
additional option, income advantage, an
innovative index structured settlement.
Along with many [music] of the benefits
that structured settlements deliver,
income advantage provides the
opportunity to achieve market-based
[music] gains with growth linked to the
S&P 500 index while also protecting
[music] against market declines. And
it's backed by the strength of
Credential, a highly rated [music]
insurance company. These benefits can
make a positive difference in helping
you move forward with greater
confidence. [music]
Let's look at how Income Advantage
works. Your payments [music] are
deferred until a date in the future.
During this deferral period, Income
Advantage is linked to the S&P 500, an
[music] index that tracks the
performance of the 500 largest companies
listed on the US stock exchanges.
Changes in [music] the S&P 500 are
measured in 1, 2, or [music] 5-year
increments called index terms, which you
select.
At the end of each index term, [music]
any growth is credited up to a maximum
called a cap rate. It works like this.
If the S&P [music] 500 increases by an
amount less than the cap rate, interest
[music] credited will equal the S&P 500
percentage change.
If the S&P 500 [music] increases by an
amount greater than or equal to the cap
rate, interest credited will equal the
cap rate. With income advantage, you're
also protected in case the S&P [music]
500 declines.
This means if the S&P 500 decreases or
is unchanged, no interest is [music]
credited and any previously credited
interest is preserved.
The premium plus any [music] interest
credited is called the accumulation
amount. This amount [music] will never
decrease.
It will never dip below the premium
amount and you will not lose any [music]
previously credited interest. At the end
of the deferral period, the final
accumulation amount will be multiplied
by a [music] predetermined payout rate
to determine the annual payment amount.
The payment amount is fixed [music]
throughout the payout period and all
payments are guaranteed and income
[music] tax-free.
Think Income Advantage might be the
right option for you? A structured
[music] settlement consultant will work
with you to design a settlement plan
that meets your needs and help you
decide [music] how much of your
settlement to allocate to Income
Advantage,
how long to defer your payments,
the index [music] term,
and finally how many years to receive
payments and how often. Payments [music]
can be made annually, semiannually,
quarterly, or monthly.
Credential [music] has been helping
individuals achieve and maintain
financial wellness and security.
[music] We can help you look forward to
a future filled with greater potential
and possibility. For more information
[music] on how Income Advantage can help
you, contact your attorney or structured
settlement consultant.
>> [music]